Ravi Kiran KC

Technical Writer/Information Developer

E-mail: Ravikiran_24@yahoo.com **Mobile:** +91 7348851546

OBJECTIVE

To deliver beautiful and user-centric help documents. I bring to bear my technical writing experience to understand the unique documentation requirements, collaborate with subject matter experts to gather information and develop help content. Marked precision and attractive document design are the hallmarks of my work.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Documented user guides, installation guides, configuration guides, getting started guides, integration guides, release notes/software change notice
- Hands-on experience in API documentation
- Publish documents in PDF and online help formats
- Hands-on experience in video scripting and creating videos for instructional videos
- Knowledgeable about DITA XML and Structured concepts
- Well-versed in single-sourcing and topic-based authoring
- Ability to build rapport with SMEs and product teams
- Strong understanding of the SDLC and DDLC
- Knowledgeable about the ITSM process
- Experienced in Agile

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Authoring and Publishing: Oxygen XML, Adobe FrameMaker 2012, MadCap Flare 2017, RoboHelp, Confluence
- Video Creation: Camtasia, MadCap Mimic
- **API Testing**: Postman
- Project Management: Jira, Bitbucket, GitHub
- Capturing Tools: Snaglt, Snipping Tool, MathPix
- Programming/Scripting Languages: HTML, CSS, XML, Rest APIs, JavaScript, JSON
- Web Technology: WordPress

WORK EXPERIENCE

HCL Technologies, Bengaluru — Software Technical Writer

(July 2021 – Present)

Client: - Honeywell International

- Documented user help topics for state-of-the-art SaaS and on-premises applications
- Wrote for a variety of audiences, including Project Engineers, SaaSOps teams, IT administrators, and end-customers
- Interviewed subject matter experts and built rapport with the product team to understand how the application works
- Followed technical documentation standards such as MSTP and Simplified Technical English

- Delivered documents in PDF, web-based online help, and CHM formats
- Worked with HTML and CSS to customize the document design and created landing pages for Help Files
- Implemented context-sensitive online help
- Created thirty-plus instructional videos
- Migrated from non-XML content to DITA XML (around 2500 pages)
- Used Oxygen XML, Confluence, MadCap Flare, Camtasia, and Adobe FrameMaker to deliver text and video-based user help documents in PDF and online help formats

Hetero Healthcare, Bengaluru — BDM

(Feb 2020 – June 2021)

- Edited and rebranded the PowerPoint, USP, training materials, and web content for the marketing team
- Collaborated closely with internal teams and sales to determine the functionality and design features of the product
- Tracking the sales figures, handling product-related queries from global clients, and giving them on-time resolution

Zydus, Bengaluru — **Executive**

(Mar 2018 – July 2019)

- Worked and collaborated with the marketing coordinator to set up and manage email campaigns and manage the contact list through valuable segmentation
- Tracking the sales figures, handling product-related queries from global clients, and giving them on-time resolution

Emcure, Bengaluru — TM

(Jan 2017 – Feb 2018)

- Measure brand awareness and perception and ensure clear, actionable data and feedback to evaluate campaigns and inform future initiatives
- Created and executed brand marketing campaigns

MPS Ltd, Bengaluru — Technical Editor/ Writer

(Feb 2013 – Oct 2016)

Client: - Elsevier

- Edited and updated the technical information content according to the set standards regarding order, clarity, conciseness, style, and terminology
- Followed style guide standards such as the Chicago Manual of Style, MSTP, and Simplified Technical English
- Quality review of the final product as per the checklist
- Published guides and creating online help files using Adobe FrameMaker and RoboHelp

EDUCATION

- MCA (Master of Computer Application) from Karnataka State Open University in 2016
- BSc (Computer Science) from Bengaluru University in 2012

CERTIFICATES

- Certified Professional Technical Writing in 2015 from System Domain
- Certified API Technical Writing: Rest APIs in 2019 from Udemy
- Certified JavaScript in 2023 from Guvi IIT
- Certified Agile development Crash course in 2023 from Udemy

Date:

Place: Bengaluru Ravi Kiran KC